<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacksonville Real Estate Video Blog with Jeff Riber</title>
    <description>You're probably looking for someone to help you make a good decision on your next real estate transaction, yes? Theodore Roosevelt (our 26th President) has this quote that I love, “Every person who invests in well-selected real estate in a growing section of a prosperous community adopts the surest and safest method of becoming independent, for real estate is the basis of wealth.” If your aim is to improve your well being, and the well being of your family, then home-ownership is a great way (if not the best way) to do it!

We know that good decisions are made with good information. Just like many other categories of our economy, residential real estate has become a very specialized skill. Making sure that you have a skilled professional alongside you when buying or selling is critical. Mistakes can be costly.

I am a self-proclaimed Internet Marketing Connoisseur, grew up in Jacksonville (minus 4 years in Virginia getting a degree in Finance from Liberty University) and love almost everything about the real estate business. I have a tendency to try and do things that people tell me I shouldn't. Thus, jumping into the real estate business during the &quot;Great Recession&quot; was a pretty predictable move. I've been working as a real estate agent since 2007 (prior to that I was in the mortgage business) and became the broker/owner of ERA Heavener Realty in 2011. At this point, I'm well past 400 closings in my career, and have personally bought/sold over 50 homes. In 2010 I was honored to have been nominated to the Jacksonville Business Journals 40 Under 40 crew. All of that to say, I've taken all of the bumps and bruises the real estate market has to offer, so that I can help you avoid them :)

In addition to real estate, I love traveling with my wife to cool places, hanging out with our little ones (Anniston, Miles, and Ava, and two more on the way!), and playing basketball (even though I have lost a step... Or, two).</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 13:46:37 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 13:46:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Want a More Comprehensive Look at the Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kxGqz2W0ThA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s why the Housing Affordability Index is a great tool for buyers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the questions that I field on an almost daily basis is, “When is the right time to make a move in the market?” &lt;strong&gt;There’s no objectively superior time to buy or sell in the market&lt;/strong&gt;; it’s more a question of, “When is the right time &lt;em&gt;for me&lt;/em&gt;?” Perhaps you’re downsizing because the kids have left the nest, upgrading because your young family is growing, or you’re just ready for a change. As your Realtor, I can’t help you with any of those personal decisions, but there’s one important thing I can give you to inform those decisions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every month, the National Association of Realtors puts out a report called the Housing Affordability Index (HAI). In addition to factoring in the current median price of single-family homes, it accounts for mortgage interest rates and median income, as well as qualifying income, which is basically a measure of what mortgage companies are requiring of borrowers these days. Therefore, the HAI provides us with a more holistic view of what’s going on in the real estate market and helps homebuyers understand their true purchasing power. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always keep up with this report because it offers some incredibly useful information. &lt;strong&gt;At 1:35 in the video above, you’ll be able to see an example of this index&lt;/strong&gt; (for simplicity’s sake, we’ll be checking out the national numbers, as our local Jacksonville market would require more data points). The higher the affordability index value, the more purchasing power consumers have in the real estate market. The lowest this index ever got was back in 2006 when it hit just above 100 nationally. That meant it was particularly difficult for people to purchase a home at a median price point based on incomes because prices were quite high but interest rates weren’t helping anyone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The HAI provides us with a more holistic view of what’s going on in the real estate market.%20http://localhost:4000/want-a-more-comprehensive-look-at-the-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The HAI provides us with a more holistic view of what’s going on in the real estate market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the highest this index ever got was in 2013, when it topped out at 210 or so—a phenomenal time to be a homebuyer. A comparison of the data from 2017 through 2020 reveals that &lt;strong&gt;homes haven’t become all that much more affordable despite historic drops in the interest rates.&lt;/strong&gt; (In October 2020, the last month for which we have complete data, the index stood at 167.2, as compared to 157.9 in 2017). There is a shortage of inventory in most markets but demand remains high thanks to low interest rates; consequently, prices just keep rising, which has, in turn, kept the home affordability index from going up by a larger degree. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The market has a funny way of balancing out all of these complex, interconnected variables.&lt;/strong&gt; While the HAI has certainly changed over the past few years, those changes have not been dramatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious to see this interesting concept applied to your selling and buying plans, feel free to reach out by phone or email anytime. I’d be happy to break these numbers down further and explain what they may mean for your particular circumstances and goals. I’m here to help, and I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 10:28:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/want-a-more-comprehensive-look-at-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/want-a-more-comprehensive-look-at-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Florida Homeowners Insurance Rates Are Rising</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ucbt5MoB2g8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s an overview of why homeowners insurance costs are rising in FL.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month or so ago, I was having a conversation with Danny Sands, owner of Brightway Insurance, who told me that homeowners insurance rates were about to go up. That was the first time I had heard such news, so it didn’t quite sink in then. Sure enough, though, I soon started seeing articles in real estate publications about the coming insurance rate climb, so I’ve invited Danny to chat publicly about the problem and discuss potential solutions for homeowners. Unfortunately, as Danny explains, it’s not just one issue affecting the homeowners insurance market here in Florida—it’s a multi-headed beast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:04 — What is “reinsurance,” and why are reinsurance costs a big part of the problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:03 — Legal issues exclusive to Florida (the only state that allows multipliers for attorney fees)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:48 — Roof claims are forcing insurance companies to make tough business decisions &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:25 — Pro tip: Work with a savvy agent and stay up to date on your roof and water heater &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:11 — The importance of reassessing your dwelling coverage to avoid being overinsured &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:18 — Citizens Property Insurance: the company of last resort created by the state of Florida&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:50 — Wrapping up today’s discussion with Danny’s insurance forecast &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News of rising insurance costs is obviously a huge buzzkill, but what else would we expect from 2020 at this point? Let’s just be thankful for our properties and the coverage we do have, and take the necessary steps to guard ourselves against a market in flux. I hope you found this update from Danny helpful; if you want to hear more from him on this topic, &lt;strong&gt;give him a ring at 904-999-3250.&lt;/strong&gt; As always, you can give me a call or send an email with any real estate-related concerns or questions. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 14:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/florida-homeowners-insurance-rates-are-rising.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/florida-homeowners-insurance-rates-are-rising.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Message of Thanks to All of You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WZFhQRdWSJs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a quick message of gratitude as we approach Thanksgiving.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s once again that season where we take time to pause and reflect on what we’re grateful for, which is especially important in this turbulent year.  First, I want to say thank you for all of your support for our team; we wouldn’t be where we are today without you. I also wanted to share a quote with you from G.K. Chesterton: “When it comes to life, the critical thing is whether you take things for granted or take them with gratitude.” No matter what comes our way, we can still find ways to be thankful, and I wanted to pass that along to you this holiday season. To hear my full Thanksgiving message, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 10:24:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-message-of-thanks-to-all-of-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-message-of-thanks-to-all-of-you.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are My Top 5 Tips for Dealing With Multiple Offers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fBuTJQtPybg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple offers are a nice problem; here are some tips that will help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve paid any attention to the news lately regarding real estate, you know we’re in a very hot seller’s market. Due to this, houses that are listed in a good area and are priced appropriately will have multiple offers. How do you navigate these offers and pick the best one? Here are my tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Take a look at the environment you’re in.&lt;/strong&gt; Calculate the absorption rate first, which is the measure of supply and demand for your particular area. If you look back at the previous six months of sales, it will give you a better idea. For example, let’s say you live in a planned-unit development that has had 10 sales in the last six months with two active listings. We know that they’re selling just shy of two units per month and can come to the conclusion that you have just over one month of inventory. In a normal market, there are around six months of inventory. When inventory is significantly less than 6 months you are in a strong sellers market.  And, the opposite is true, when it rises above 6 months you’re in a buyers market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Time the listing.&lt;/strong&gt; We like to do this so that our clients are appropriately navigating the market. We want to get the most traffic without losing the initial drive and demand for a new listing. I like to list homes on Thursdays because a majority of buyers want to look at homes in person on the weekend. Putting your home online on a Thursday gives buyers two days to find it, another day or so to make an offer on it, and another day or so for you to accept that offer. By Monday, your home could be under contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers are motivated to buy well-priced, move-in ready homes.%20http://localhost:4000/what-are-my-top-5-tips-for-dealing-with-multiple-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers are motivated to buy well-priced, move-in ready homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Put your best foot forward.&lt;/strong&gt; In the past, I’ve seen plenty of houses hitting the market before they’re ready and still try to get top dollar. You can’t do that in today’s market. Buyers are motivated, but they’re motivated to buy a move-in ready home that doesn’t need a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Plan the response.&lt;/strong&gt; Once you receive all your offers and analyze the price and terms of each to figure out which is the best offer for your situation, it’s time to negotiate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Negotiate.&lt;/strong&gt; Many sellers think you just have to pick the highest-priced offer. Inevitably, there is not always a clear winner when many bidders are involved. One offer could have a higher price but come with a contingency. You can go back to this buyer and let them know you like their offer, but won’t accept it with the contingency, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my best tips for navigating this crazy market as a seller. If you need more advice or have any real estate questions I can answer, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 09:40:12 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-my-top-5-tips-for-dealing-with-multiple-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-my-top-5-tips-for-dealing-with-multiple-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does the Half-Cent Sales Tax Referendum Affect You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2jI6z7b5_8o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have questions about the half-cent sales tax referendum? Shannon Beckham has answers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you need to know about the upcoming half-cent sales tax referendum? Today I’m joined by Shannon Beckham, a former teacher and mother of two children enrolled in the Duval County public school system, to answer that question. I had questions myself about this referendum, and I was directed to Shannon through a mutual friend. She has no dog in this fight, and she’s as well-informed about the issue as anyone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:06—A little background on Shannon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:45—A general overview of the half-cent sales tax referendum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:11—How Duval County differs from other counties in terms of keeping up with renovations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:13—What’s our assurance the half-cent sales tax does what it’s supposed to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:08—What outcome Shannon is expecting &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:40—How the broken windows theory applies to this situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:13—Final thoughts from Shannon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:00—Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 08:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-does-the-half-cent-sales-tax-referendum-affect-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-does-the-half-cent-sales-tax-referendum-affect-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Local</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has COVID Impacted Landlord Rights?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tAKqoNxIbbc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seth Rosenstein breaks down what property owners/managers must know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For today’s message, I’m thankful to be accompanied by Matt Miller of ERA, our property manager, and Seth Rothstein, who’s an attorney and partner at Adams, Rothstein &amp;amp; Siegel. Seth focuses on real estate and civil litigation and has several landlords as clients. Starting in April, the first full month of the pandemic in the U.S., there were a series of mandates that impacted landlords’ rights and created plenty of confusion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an order issued by Chief Judge Mahan, orders from Governor DeSantis, the CARES Act, and now the CDC order. Seth has been combing through updates that have been flooding in on an almost daily basis to keep his clients protected. Today Seth’s sharing the latest legal news as it pertains to property owners and managers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:33 — Setting the record straight on commercial property, expired leases, and noncompliance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:00 — The CDC’s 41-page document: What it requires, and the circumstances that created it &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:23 — Are tenants making their best efforts to make partial payments? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:27 — Explaining the legal term ‘force majeure’ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:07 — What solutions do landlords have at their disposal? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:30 —When will things return to normal? How can property owners stay ahead of the curve? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:15 — Have things reached a fever pitch? Will there be cases like “Landlords v. __ County”? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:14 — Wrapping up our discussion &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, Seth’s legal insight has helped you get a better understanding of how all of the recent government orders affect you as a property owner or manager. If you have further questions on this or any other real estate-related topic, reach out to us via phone or email. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 16:12:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-has-covid-impacted-landlord-rights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-has-covid-impacted-landlord-rights.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Save Money on Your Property Taxes?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Cvv01zSq10?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how you can save money on your property taxes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering how to save money on your property taxes, there are a couple of ways to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;you could always let someone else do it.&lt;/strong&gt; There are several companies (&lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.firstcoastconsultants.com/&quot;&gt;First Coast Consultants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, for example) dedicated to helping you lower your property taxes. Their primary focus is larger commercial properties, but they can help you as well, provided you’re willing to pay a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;establish that you have a discrepancy.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can prove that the county is assessing your property for more than it’s worth, and thus charging you more in taxes than what you should be paying, then they’ll lower the value—and by extension, your taxes. If you decide on this option, give me a call; I’d be happy to craft a market analysis to help you state your case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to act to contest your property’s valuation.%20http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to act to contest your property’s valuation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, once a discrepancy is established, &lt;strong&gt;know when to act.&lt;/strong&gt; August has just ended, so you should’ve received a notice of proposed taxes from the county by now telling you what they intend to tax you on this November. This means right now is the time to act if you want to contest your property’s valuation. You can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.coj.net/departments/regulatory-boards-and-commissions/value-adjustment-board&quot;&gt;contact the Value Adjustment Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; either through the online form or by sending them an email.  Their offices are presently closed due to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;remember to fill out the proper paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you fill out the petition form completely and correctly when contesting your assessed value. There’s a slight fee involved, but it’s well worth it if you can save thousands of dollars later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 15:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Can You Improve Your Offer Without Paying More?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bb8YSKhbupA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;So how do you improve your offer without simply raising your price?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some key tips to help you find success as a buyer in today’s market—without simply paying more for the home you want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Be flexible with your timeline.&lt;/strong&gt; Being flexible means, being willing to close sooner or later, depending on what the seller wants. If necessary, sellers might ask to stay in the house for a bit longer after closing. That may not be ideal, but if it doesn’t cost you more money and it gets the deal done, it’s something to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Raise your earnest money amount.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers typically see this as a sign that the buyer is serious. Since the buyer won’t get that money back if they back out of the deal for some non-contractual reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Shorten or remove your contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; Your could shorten the inspection contingency from it’s usual 10 days down 7, as an example. Additionally, you could shorten the financing contingency to put the sellers mind at ease well in advance of closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Move fast.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had multiple deals recently where a buyer will find a property they like one day, only to find out that it has several offers on it the next day. If you want your deal done, in today’s market, you have to move very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Share your story.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not a sentimental person myself, but sentimentality does often mean something to homeowners. Especially if they’ve lived in that home as their primary residence for a long time. To know that the next group that’s going to live there, take care of it, and be as attentive to it as the owners themselves were can make all the difference in a seller’s decision to accept an offer. Write them a letter and share relevant details about your life that you think would be compelling to the owner and their situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Be fully approved.&lt;/strong&gt; The pandemic has created a mess for mortgage companies and banks as they approve buyers to get loans. You can go all of the way through the underwriting process prior to making offers. That way, the seller won’t have to worry about the deal falling through for some underwriting issue later on during the deal’s timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information about how to successfully navigate a deal in today’s market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. I’d be happy to talk strategy with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 09:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-improve-your-offer-without-paying-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-improve-your-offer-without-paying-more.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Movies That Help Us Get Through Quarantine</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sbbtx2N5-Cs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re taking a step back from hardcore business information to talk about something a little different. Matt Miller, ERA’s property manager, and Zach Corson, the transaction manager, join me to talk about quarantine movies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever do business with us, you’ll probably cross paths with one of these two, but instead of picking their brains for expertise about real estate transactions, I wanted to talk about their favorite movies to help get them through these tough times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are each of their top three favorite movies to rewatch during quarantine:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caddyshack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy Gilmore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major League II&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Star Wars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My own picks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Man on Fire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inception&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¡Three Amigos!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of a way to keep yourself entertained, check out our top movie picks! Hopefully they’ll help brighten your week as things start to return to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions about real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re here to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 16:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/movies-that-help-us-get-through-quarantine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/movies-that-help-us-get-through-quarantine.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yard to Table Farms Empowers Homeowners to Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hfVdqvS2Krg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s everything you need to know about Brian’s customizable gardens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sat down with Brian Friederichs, owner of Yard to Table Farms, to discuss his amazing garden box business model that empowers people to believe in their own green thumb and grow amazing veggies. About a month ago, Brain came over to my house with a garden box he built himself, and our kids love it; we now have some nearly ripe tomatoes, squash, rosemary, and other herbs as well. He explains the lack of plant diversity in our mass-production supermarket model, the tasty boons of homegrown snacks, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message, or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:11 — When (and how) Brian fell in love with the micro-farm and square-foot gardening model&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00 — How Brian was able to bring his business model to market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:10 — Where Brian offers his services, and the importance of choosing the right wood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:37 — What, if anything, can you plant in June?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:44 — How much time and effort is required to maintain your garden box?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:10 — Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reach out to Brian at Yard to Table Farms by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yttfarms.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;yttfarms.com&lt;/a&gt; and filling out an online inquiry or calling the direct numbers listed on the site. As always, give me a call, text, or email if you have any questions about real estate or the status of our market. I look forward to hearing from you! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/yard-to-table-farms-empowers-homeowners-to-garden.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/yard-to-table-farms-empowers-homeowners-to-garden.html</guid>
        
        <category>Local</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
