<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacksonville Real Estate Video Blog with Jeff Riber</title>
    <description>You're probably looking for someone to help you make a good decision on your next real estate transaction, yes? Theodore Roosevelt (our 26th President) has this quote that I love, “Every person who invests in well-selected real estate in a growing section of a prosperous community adopts the surest and safest method of becoming independent, for real estate is the basis of wealth.” If your aim is to improve your well being, and the well being of your family, then home-ownership is a great way (if not the best way) to do it!

We know that good decisions are made with good information. Just like many other categories of our economy, residential real estate has become a very specialized skill. Making sure that you have a skilled professional alongside you when buying or selling is critical. Mistakes can be costly.

I am a self-proclaimed Internet Marketing Connoisseur, grew up in Jacksonville (minus 4 years in Virginia getting a degree in Finance from Liberty University) and love almost everything about the real estate business. I have a tendency to try and do things that people tell me I shouldn't. Thus, jumping into the real estate business during the &quot;Great Recession&quot; was a pretty predictable move. I've been working as a real estate agent since 2007 (prior to that I was in the mortgage business) and became the broker/owner of ERA Heavener Realty in 2011. At this point, I'm well past 400 closings in my career, and have personally bought/sold over 50 homes. In 2010 I was honored to have been nominated to the Jacksonville Business Journals 40 Under 40 crew. All of that to say, I've taken all of the bumps and bruises the real estate market has to offer, so that I can help you avoid them :)

In addition to real estate, I love traveling with my wife to cool places, hanging out with our little ones (Anniston, Miles, and Ava), and playing basketball (even though I have lost a step... Or, two).</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 16:27:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 16:27:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has COVID Impacted Landlord Rights?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tAKqoNxIbbc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seth Rosenstein breaks down what property owners/managers must know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For today’s message, I’m thankful to be accompanied by Matt Miller of ERA, our property manager, and Seth Rothstein, who’s an attorney and partner at Adams, Rothstein &amp;amp; Siegel. Seth focuses on real estate and civil litigation and has several landlords as clients. Starting in April, the first full month of the pandemic in the U.S., there were a series of mandates that impacted landlords’ rights and created plenty of confusion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an order issued by Chief Judge Mahan, orders from Governor DeSantis, the CARES Act, and now the CDC order. Seth has been combing through updates that have been flooding in on an almost daily basis to keep his clients protected. Today Seth’s sharing the latest legal news as it pertains to property owners and managers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:33 — Setting the record straight on commercial property, expired leases, and noncompliance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:00 — The CDC’s 41-page document: What it requires, and the circumstances that created it &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:23 — Are tenants making their best efforts to make partial payments? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:27 — Explaining the legal term ‘force majeure’ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:07 — What solutions do landlords have at their disposal? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:30 —When will things return to normal? How can property owners stay ahead of the curve? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:15 — Have things reached a fever pitch? Will there be cases like “Landlords v. __ County”? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:14 — Wrapping up our discussion &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, Seth’s legal insight has helped you get a better understanding of how all of the recent government orders affect you as a property owner or manager. If you have further questions on this or any other real estate-related topic, reach out to us via phone or email. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 16:12:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-has-covid-impacted-landlord-rights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-has-covid-impacted-landlord-rights.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Save Money on Your Property Taxes?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Cvv01zSq10?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how you can save money on your property taxes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering how to save money on your property taxes, there are a couple of ways to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;you could always let someone else do it.&lt;/strong&gt; There are several companies (&lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.firstcoastconsultants.com/&quot;&gt;First Coast Consultants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, for example) dedicated to helping you lower your property taxes. Their primary focus is larger commercial properties, but they can help you as well, provided you’re willing to pay a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;establish that you have a discrepancy.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can prove that the county is assessing your property for more than it’s worth, and thus charging you more in taxes than what you should be paying, then they’ll lower the value—and by extension, your taxes. If you decide on this option, give me a call; I’d be happy to craft a market analysis to help you state your case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to act to contest your property’s valuation.%20http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to act to contest your property’s valuation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, once a discrepancy is established, &lt;strong&gt;know when to act.&lt;/strong&gt; August has just ended, so you should’ve received a notice of proposed taxes from the county by now telling you what they intend to tax you on this November. This means right now is the time to act if you want to contest your property’s valuation. You can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.coj.net/departments/regulatory-boards-and-commissions/value-adjustment-board&quot;&gt;contact the Value Adjustment Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; either through the online form or by sending them an email.  Their offices are presently closed due to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;remember to fill out the proper paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you fill out the petition form completely and correctly when contesting your assessed value. There’s a slight fee involved, but it’s well worth it if you can save thousands of dollars later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 15:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Can You Improve Your Offer Without Paying More?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bb8YSKhbupA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;So how do you improve your offer without simply raising your price?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some key tips to help you find success as a buyer in today’s market—without simply paying more for the home you want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Be flexible with your timeline.&lt;/strong&gt; Being flexible means, being willing to close sooner or later, depending on what the seller wants. If necessary, sellers might ask to stay in the house for a bit longer after closing. That may not be ideal, but if it doesn’t cost you more money and it gets the deal done, it’s something to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Raise your earnest money amount.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers typically see this as a sign that the buyer is serious. Since the buyer won’t get that money back if they back out of the deal for some non-contractual reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Shorten or remove your contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; Your could shorten the inspection contingency from it’s usual 10 days down 7, as an example. Additionally, you could shorten the financing contingency to put the sellers mind at ease well in advance of closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Move fast.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had multiple deals recently where a buyer will find a property they like one day, only to find out that it has several offers on it the next day. If you want your deal done, in today’s market, you have to move very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Share your story.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not a sentimental person myself, but sentimentality does often mean something to homeowners. Especially if they’ve lived in that home as their primary residence for a long time. To know that the next group that’s going to live there, take care of it, and be as attentive to it as the owners themselves were can make all the difference in a seller’s decision to accept an offer. Write them a letter and share relevant details about your life that you think would be compelling to the owner and their situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Be fully approved.&lt;/strong&gt; The pandemic has created a mess for mortgage companies and banks as they approve buyers to get loans. You can go all of the way through the underwriting process prior to making offers. That way, the seller won’t have to worry about the deal falling through for some underwriting issue later on during the deal’s timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information about how to successfully navigate a deal in today’s market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. I’d be happy to talk strategy with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 09:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-improve-your-offer-without-paying-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-improve-your-offer-without-paying-more.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Movies That Help Us Get Through Quarantine</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sbbtx2N5-Cs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re taking a step back from hardcore business information to talk about something a little different. Matt Miller, ERA’s property manager, and Zach Corson, the transaction manager, join me to talk about quarantine movies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever do business with us, you’ll probably cross paths with one of these two, but instead of picking their brains for expertise about real estate transactions, I wanted to talk about their favorite movies to help get them through these tough times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are each of their top three favorite movies to rewatch during quarantine:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caddyshack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy Gilmore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major League II&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Star Wars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My own picks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Man on Fire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inception&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¡Three Amigos!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of a way to keep yourself entertained, check out our top movie picks! Hopefully they’ll help brighten your week as things start to return to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions about real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re here to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 16:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/movies-that-help-us-get-through-quarantine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/movies-that-help-us-get-through-quarantine.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yard to Table Farms Empowers Homeowners to Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hfVdqvS2Krg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s everything you need to know about Brian’s customizable gardens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sat down with Brian Friederichs, owner of Yard to Table Farms, to discuss his amazing garden box business model that empowers people to believe in their own green thumb and grow amazing veggies. About a month ago, Brain came over to my house with a garden box he built himself, and our kids love it; we now have some nearly ripe tomatoes, squash, rosemary, and other herbs as well. He explains the lack of plant diversity in our mass-production supermarket model, the tasty boons of homegrown snacks, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message, or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:11 — When (and how) Brian fell in love with the micro-farm and square-foot gardening model&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00 — How Brian was able to bring his business model to market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:10 — Where Brian offers his services, and the importance of choosing the right wood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:37 — What, if anything, can you plant in June?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:44 — How much time and effort is required to maintain your garden box?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:10 — Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reach out to Brian at Yard to Table Farms by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yttfarms.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;yttfarms.com&lt;/a&gt; and filling out an online inquiry or calling the direct numbers listed on the site. As always, give me a call, text, or email if you have any questions about real estate or the status of our market. I look forward to hearing from you! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/yard-to-table-farms-empowers-homeowners-to-garden.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/yard-to-table-farms-empowers-homeowners-to-garden.html</guid>
        
        <category>Local</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Do the Latest Stats Say About Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MrIfzXNBOwA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the latest market stats you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s happening in our Northeast Florida real estate market as we head into the summer season? Today I have the latest statistics to share with you. First, we’ll look at mortgage interest rates and showing activity, then we’ll check the median sale price and supply and demand statistics. Finally, we’ll go over the statewide unemployment numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:49—Mortgage interest rates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:47—Showing activity &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:08—Supply and demand &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:07—Median sale price &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:35—The current unemployment rate &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:01—What do these numbers mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:57—Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about our market or are thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 14:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-do-the-latest-stats-say-about-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-do-the-latest-stats-say-about-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Your Morning Routine?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GR6uyeAIte8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, our team read the book “The Miracle Morning” by Hal Elrod and began learning a lot about how we should be starting our days. &lt;strong&gt;Then we went into quarantine and our morning routines exploded.&lt;/strong&gt; Now that we’re getting out of quarantine, we’re getting back to our morning routines and I wanted to share it with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The morning routine Hal teaches is broken down into six activities with the acronym S.A.V.E.R.S.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what they stand for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silence:&lt;/strong&gt; Using prayer and meditation to bring calmness to the start of our day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affirmations:&lt;/strong&gt; These are the things that you want to achieve that you’re creating an audible reminder for yourself on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualization:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s all sorts of research showing that with practice visualizing physical tasks (like your golf swing), you can make substantial improvements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise:&lt;/strong&gt; We all know we need to do it.  Knock it out first thing so you don’t forget!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading:&lt;/strong&gt; “You will be the same person in five years as you are today except for the people you meet and the books you read.” ― Charlie Tremendous Jones&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scribing (writing):&lt;/strong&gt; Clear writing is the result of clear thinking. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Starting the day with a bit of silence is key.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-your-morning-routine.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Starting the day with a bit of silence is key.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the six things that he picked out for the perfect morning routine. You don’t have to do everything every day, but starting with one or two of these things in the morning and slowly adding to the list as time goes on will enhance your day, and ultimately your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about my morning routine or anything else that you’re doing in the morning that you think we should be doing too, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-your-morning-routine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-your-morning-routine.html</guid>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Overview of Closing Costs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EGTH4QPhAF0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who pays for which closing costs in a real estate transaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I answer that question, a quick reminder: there is no law stating which party has to pay a particular cost. What we’re talking about is the customary costs for a particular location. Different market areas have different customs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is what’s customary for sellers to pay in Northeast Florida:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deed stamps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This state tax constitutes 0.007% of the sale price. It’s a set rate, so there’s no negotiating it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owners title insurance policy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This is also a state-regulated amount that basically provides insurance to the new buyer so that if any issues arise from previous ownership, it’s taken care of by the title insurance company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title search:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; The title company, in general, will handle the transaction as a whole, including the search and organizing the title insurance policy, which brings me to our next item…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement fee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This is what the title company charges for doing the work mentioned above and handling the money, which goes from the lender to the seller, and then the seller to their lender, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey fee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This shows the buyer what they actually own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other costs that are sometimes asked of seller’s to pay include: the &lt;em&gt;satisfaction of the mortgage&lt;/em&gt; (if they have one) to pay off their existing loan, &lt;em&gt;courier fees&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;wire fees&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;em&gt;home warranty&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;seller paid closing costs on behalf of the buyer&lt;/em&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, buyers pay for anything associated with getting financing in Northeast Florida, so if you’re paying cash to purchase your home, your closing costs are minimal (recording fees, wiring fees, etc.). If you’re using financing to purchase though, you’ll be expected to cover several fees in addition to that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intangible tax:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This is a tax on getting a mortgage, and it goes toward the state coffers. 0.002 * the loan amount.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note stamps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This is like the deed stamps, except against the amount of the loan just a different amount. 0.0035 * loan amount.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgagee title insurance policy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This is similar to the owner’s title insurance policy, except it protects the lender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title insurance endorsements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; These are smaller modifications to your title insurance policy that protect you from issues that might arise if you live in a homeowners association or condominium complex, as an example.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspection fees:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; Whether it’s a general inspection, WDO inspection, pool inspection, etc., these are usually paid outside of the closing. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage origination charges:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; When you borrow money from a bank or mortgage company, this is the fee you pay them for originating your loan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appraisal fee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This is the fee you pay your lender so they can hire an appraiser to substantiate the amount you’re paying for the home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage Insurance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; This applies if you’re putting less than 20% down. Depending on the loan type, different terminology is used to describe the same function.  On FHA loans it’s MIP (mortgage insurance premium). For a VA loan, this is referred to as a funding fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other miscellaneous buyer costs can include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home warranty fee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lender’s flood certification&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wire fee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Municipal lien search fee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estoppel letter fee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see a more in-depth description of these costs, follow this link that takes you to &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.904living.com/selling/what-closing-costs-do-i-pay-when-i-sell-my-home/&quot;&gt;my blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. Remember, everything in real estate is negotiable—you never know what the other party is willing to pay for &lt;strong&gt;until you ask&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 13:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-overview-of-closing-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-overview-of-closing-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To sell or not to sell? That is our question today</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_zVHi7J8Bu8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the scenario.  You’re thinking about making a move, but can’t decide if you should sell your existing home or rent it out.  Assuming you’re financially capable of moving without selling, which should you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’ll discuss the pros and cons of each, and give you some insight that will help you make the best possible decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will set up a scenario in the video that is very realistic.  Obviously, it won’t match your situation exactly.  If you would like for me to run the numbers on your particular plan, just give me a call!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or use the timestamps I’ve provided below to navigate the discussion at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:54—When you purchased the house originally&lt;br /&gt;2:37—What you could rent your home for in today’s market&lt;br /&gt;3:12—The responsibilities, benefits, and expected return of renting out the property&lt;br /&gt;4:25—Property depreciation as a taxable loss&lt;br /&gt;5:51—Thoughts about renting for a short period of time&lt;br /&gt;7:14—Alternative investment options&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this information helps you (or someone you know) to make a good decision with your next move. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to chat with you about your options.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/to-sell-or-not-to-sell-that-is-our-question-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/to-sell-or-not-to-sell-that-is-our-question-today.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discussion With Riber Financial</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JcRy-IyVJ0w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Blake Riber, owner of Riber Financial, joins me on Facebook Live to discuss the Small Business Administration (SBA) program and the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) rollout for stimulus funds. One of the most frequent questions we’re hearing from people right now is how to access the money from these programs to keep their businesses operating. There is $349 billion available for small businesses. If you’re a small business with 500 or fewer employees, you’re most likely eligible to receive funds. The government will take your average monthly 2019 salary costs from your company, multiply it by 2.5%, and that’s your loan base. To learn more about these programs, watch my latest video above. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 09:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/discussion-with-riber-financial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/discussion-with-riber-financial.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
