<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacksonville Real Estate Video Blog with Jeff Riber</title>
    <description>You're probably looking for someone to help you make a good decision on your next real estate transaction, yes? Theodore Roosevelt (our 26th President) has this quote that I love, “Every person who invests in well-selected real estate in a growing section of a prosperous community adopts the surest and safest method of becoming independent, for real estate is the basis of wealth.” If your aim is to improve your well being, and the well being of your family, then home-ownership is a great way (if not the best way) to do it!

We know that good decisions are made with good information. Just like many other categories of our economy, residential real estate has become a very specialized skill. Making sure that you have a skilled professional alongside you when buying or selling is critical. Mistakes can be costly.

I grew up in Jacksonville (minus 4 years in Virginia getting a degree in Finance from Liberty University) and love almost everything about the real estate business. I have a tendency to try and do things that people tell me I shouldn't. Thus, jumping into the real estate business during the &quot;Great Recession&quot; was a pretty predictable move. I've been working as a real estate agent since 2007 (prior to that I was in the mortgage business) and became the broker/owner of ERA Heavener Realty in 2011. At this point, I'm well past 400 closings in my career, and have personally bought/sold over 50 homes. In 2010 I was honored to have been nominated to the Jacksonville Business Journals 40 Under 40 crew. All of that to say, I've taken all of the bumps and bruises the real estate market has to offer, so that I can help you avoid them :)

In addition to real estate, I love traveling with my wife to cool places, hanging out with our little ones (Anniston, Miles, Ava, Lily, and Leighton),  and playing basketball (even though I have lost a step... Or, two).</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 13:41:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 13:41:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tools to Run Your Home Efficiently</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Syyg5OxOZhA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are my top five picks for must-have smart home technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to share five smart home devices that I think you’d love to have as an addition to your home. Whether you’re thinking of buying a home and want to know what to install or you’ve been in your house for years and just want to improve your experience, here are my top five recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Nest thermostat.&lt;/strong&gt; There are other brands of smart thermostats, but Nest has been my favorite. It’s user-friendly and does what you need it to without giving you a ton of confusing and unnecessary options. It has the capacity to change the temperature of your home when you’re gone and lets you change settings while you’re sitting in bed at night. Even better, it’s not much more expensive than your average thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The myQ garage opener&lt;/strong&gt;. The Chamberlain myQ remote garage door opening system operates from an app on your phone that allows you to do all sorts of things. For example, you can open the garage door for a repairman to fix something while you’re away or when you lose your keys. It also alerts you when you’ve left your garage door open, so it’s great for those who have a penchant for forgetting things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Installing smart technology could add value to your home.%20http://localhost:4000/5-tools-to-run-your-home-efficiently.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Installing smart technology could add value to your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Rachio sprinkler system.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a phenomenal product that I’ve had on our current house for over six years now. It’s as simple as installing it where your normal sprinkler controller box would be and downloading an app on your phone. It allows you to set a schedule to run the sprinklers, and it even checks the weather every day to allow you to schedule your sprinklers accordingly. No more relying on inaccurate rain gauges in the yard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Ring doorbell and floodlights.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people have a video doorbell these days. The Ring is my favorite; their app is great, and they also have a motion-detection floodlight system I enjoy. When something triggers the motion sensor, the floodlights come on, and the camera begins recording. That allows you to keep an eye on things while you’re away and record certain funny moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Magic Light Wi-Fi bulbs.&lt;/strong&gt; We put these in the lamps around the house. As long as you have a Wi-Fi connection, you’re able to control when the lights come on from your phone. The app allows you to change the brightness and color of the bulb, and you can sync the lights to music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like further recommendations for smart home technology, don’t hesitate to reach out to us by phone or email. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tools-to-run-your-home-efficiently.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-tools-to-run-your-home-efficiently.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are People Moving to Florida?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QQDXfn1F-Q0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Paul Anderson and I discuss why so many people are moving to Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m speaking with a great guest, Paul Anderson of MovingtoFloridaGuide.com. There’s been a ton of migration to Florida recently, so I figured I’d bring in an expert on the topic. Paul has tons of experience helping people move to Florida, so I’ll pick his brain about why he started doing what he does, the current state of migration, and what it all means for the future of our state. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can listen to our full conversation in the video above, or you can skip to each topic using the timestamps provided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:01 — Introducing Paul and today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:36 — Paul’s insight on people migrating to Florida&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:26 — Paul’s opinion on where things are heading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:23 — The fastest-growing cities in Florida&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:48 — The appeal of master-planned communities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:56 — The top master-planned communities for 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:31 — Why Florida is growing so rapidly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:02 — Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out Paul’s website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://movingtofloridaguide.com/&quot;&gt;https://movingtofloridaguide.com/&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions about today’s topic, please give my team a call or send us an email. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-are-people-moving-to-florida.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-are-people-moving-to-florida.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does The Future of Our Market Look Like?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sjzbpTqvbvU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what we can say about the future of Jacksonville’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe, but 2022 is already here. The Florida real estate market is hot, but what does the future look like? Today I want to give you a rundown of the numbers from 2021 and give some predictions about what our market will look like this year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can watch my full update in the video above, or you can skip to each topic using the timestamps provided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:01 - Introduction &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:51 - Zillow predicts Jacksonville will be the second-hottest market in the country in 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:43 - Statistics that predict the future of our market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:03 - People are moving to Florida from all over the country&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:34 - The future of interest rates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:39 - Prices aren’t coming down anytime soon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:05 - Wrapping up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the future of our market or how it applies to your situation, please feel free to call or email my team. We’d love to help you in any way we can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:34:17 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-does-the-future-of-our-market-look-like.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-does-the-future-of-our-market-look-like.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What To Know About CDD Fees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EaICSCvGQbg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what you need to know about CDD fees and how they’re paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are CDD fees? How do they get paid? How should we think about them? Today I’ll answer all three of these questions for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CDD stands for Community Development District.&lt;/strong&gt; When a developer comes into an area and decides to put single-family houses in a large tract of land, the cost of working on all the sewer lines, electrical, roads, and other related infrastructure can be extreme. To help with this, some developers get financing for the development and create an individual lien against each property or lot. That way, when they later sell the lot with a house to a homeowner, that homeowner inherits the debt and begins to pay it like the developer was prior to selling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CDD fees can be broken down into monthly figures, which allows you to figure out if you think it’d be worthwhile to live in a different community without such fees.%20http://localhost:4000/what-to-know-about-cdd-fees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CDD fees can be broken down into monthly figures, which allows you to figure out if you think it’d be worthwhile to live in a different community without such fees.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically you can find your CDD fees on your tax bill as a separate line item from your real estate taxes. &lt;strong&gt;CDD fees have two parts: 1) the maintenance fee&lt;/strong&gt;, which is paid in perpetuity to pay for the amenities associated with the area; and &lt;strong&gt;2) the financing fee&lt;/strong&gt;, which has an interest rate associated with it and can be paid off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 10 years ago, there was pushback against CDD fees, but now, people realize the benefits of living in a community with a CDD fee attached. CDD fees can be broken down into monthly figures, which allows you to figure out if you think it’d be worthwhile to live in a different community without such fees. Is the money you’d save worth it to live in a community without the amenities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have other questions about CDD fees or anything to do with real estate, feel free to reach out to us via phone or email. We’d love to chat with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find info on a particular CDD, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.govmgtsvc.com/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;https://www.govmgtsvc.com/contact&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-know-about-cdd-fees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-to-know-about-cdd-fees.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You For Your Support</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SUbkVWl8kdk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends,&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2021 holiday season has officially begun! We hope you are as excited as we are.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’d like to take a moment to express our gratitude to all of you this Thanksgiving&lt;/strong&gt;. We have met some truly wonderful people, and we’re proud to have helped so many reach their real estate goals over the years.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn’t be where we are today without all of your support.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your Thanksgiving dinner—that’s what we plan to do!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us if you have any real estate questions. We would be happy to help you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thank-you-for-your-support.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thank-you-for-your-support.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Top 5 Healthy Lunch Spots Around Town</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LRJATOQ4C_A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are my top five spots to get a lunch that’s tasty but also healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to take a break from hard-hitting real estate information and instead look at my top five favorite healthy lunch spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholefoodsmarket.com/stores/jacksonville&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Whole Foods.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I like their combination salad and hot bar. For $10.99 per pound (or something close to that), you can get a great salad and add chicken and veggies to make a complete lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kairosjuices.com/menu#menu=lunch-and-dinner&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Kairos.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It’s in a retail shopping just west of Hodges Blvd on the north side of Beach Boulevard. They have a lot of great stuff on the menu, but I love their Kairos Quesadilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.juicetapjax.com/menu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Juice Tap.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; They have tasty salads and juices that are also budget-conscious. My favorite is the veggie-filled greek salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grubhub.com/restaurant/southern-roots-filling-station-1275-king-st-jacksonville/1084948&quot;&gt;Southern Roots Filling Station.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re in the Riverside Avondale area, check out this vegan restaurant. My favorite item they have is their quinoa and avocado protein bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truefoodkitchen.com/menu/&quot;&gt;True Food.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This is a slightly more formal lunch gathering spot in the town center. My favorite item is the turkey burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know a healthy lunch spot, I would love to hear it so that I can put it in our rotation. If you have any real estate questions, reach out to 904-405-1995 or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jeff@era.com&quot;&gt;jeff@era.com&lt;/a&gt;. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tasty-and-healthy-lunch-spots.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-tasty-and-healthy-lunch-spots.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Brokerage Transaction Fees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7eYKSGeLXa8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what brokerage transaction fees are and why you’re charged them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you bought or sold a home and wondered, “what is a real estate brokerage transaction fee?” Do I really have to pay this extra fee? Today I’ll be answering all of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate brokerage transaction fees have been around for a while; they’re extra fees at an office level. For example, a real estate office might decide that for all transactions, they’ll charge a certain transaction fee. Typically, it’s for administrative items, marketing, document storage, and other costs of these types that the office is incurring. If the real estate agent doesn’t charge the client this fee, they’ll have to pay it themselves. These fees can range anywhere from $150 to as high as $1,200 (which is crazy), but usually, it’s within the $200 to $300 range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at ERA Heavener Realty do not charge a real estate brokerage transaction fee, so I’m a little biased against them. However, I wanted to share this information with you so that if you’re in a real estate transaction in the future with another group, you know what they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These fees can range anywhere from $150 to as high as $1,200.%20http://localhost:4000/real-estate-brokerage-transaction-fees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These fees can range anywhere from $150 to as high as $1,200.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do you have to pay these fees? I use this phrase often, and it applies here: &lt;strong&gt;Everything in real estate is negotiable.&lt;/strong&gt; So if you’re in a transaction and being charged these fees, you can certainly go to the agent or brokerage and say you don’t want to pay it. They may say you have to in order to work with them, but it’s your decision as to whether you continue working with them or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fee should be disclosed to you by your agent before buying or selling a home. At 2:40 in the video above, you can see an example of what this fee looks like on your settlement statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this fee, even if you’re in the middle of a transaction with another company, by all means, I’m happy to help and can talk you through how to handle it. Call or shoot me an email if you want to discuss transaction fees or any other real estate matter. I look forward to catching up with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/real-estate-brokerage-transaction-fees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/real-estate-brokerage-transaction-fees.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Save Money on Your Property Taxes?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TJNSgj5Uu4E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s how you can save money on your property taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering how to save money on your property taxes, there are a couple of ways to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;you could always let someone else do it.&lt;/strong&gt; There are several companies (&lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.firstcoastconsultants.com/&quot;&gt;First Coast Consultants&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowpropertytax.com/&quot;&gt;Property Tax Professionals,&lt;/a&gt; for example) dedicated to helping you lower your property taxes. Their primary focus is larger commercial properties, but they can help you as well, provided you’re willing to pay a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;establish that you have a discrepancy.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can prove that the county is assessing your property for more than it’s worth, and thus charging you more in taxes than what you should be paying, then they’ll lower the value—and by extension, your taxes. If you decide on this option, give me a call; I’d be happy to craft a market analysis to help you state your case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to act to contest your property’s valuation.%20http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to act to contest your property’s valuation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, once a discrepancy is established, &lt;strong&gt;know when to act.&lt;/strong&gt; August has just ended, so you should’ve received a notice of proposed taxes from the county by now telling you what they intend to tax you on this November. This means right now is the time to act if you want to contest your property’s valuation. You can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.coj.net/departments/regulatory-boards-and-commissions/value-adjustment-board&quot;&gt;contact the Value Adjustment Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; either through the online form or by sending them an email.  Their offices are presently closed due to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;remember to fill out the proper paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you fill out the petition form completely and correctly when contesting your assessed value. There’s a slight fee involved, but it’s well worth it if you can save thousands of dollars later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-save-money-on-your-property-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Sell Homes Using the 3 P’s</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qQtQ8IM6pO0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what you need to know to successfully sell your home this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how we ensure you as the seller receive the most money possible from your next real estate transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re selling in this market, you have more options than you’ve ever had before. Today I’m bringing clarity to the options you have, sharing some insight into how we operate as a real estate brokerage, and inviting all of your feedback along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any good baker knows. The right ingredients, in the right quantity, with the right timing, produces a great result.  Mess up during the process and you end up with something that is subpar.  That’s how we think about selling homes.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message, or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:00 — Where do we go when we’re trying to solve a problem these days?  Google.  So, what is it that you’re seeing when you head to the internet to figure out “how to sell your home in 2021?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:45 — A look at fees and costs from “iBuyers” like Opendoor and Zillow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:20 — The three P’s to help you sell your home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:00 — How we turn average homes into great products&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:35 — Our team’s pricing strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:07 — How we strategically promote homes to sell quickly and for top dollar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:00 — Our commitment to service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:25 — Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback, thoughts, or questions about selling your home in 2021, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/we-sell-homes-using-the-3-ps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/we-sell-homes-using-the-3-ps.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buyer Tips for This Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a57T81Xa_Xc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are some tips for buyers that we’ve learned over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as real estate has been bought and sold, sellers have wanted three things. They want the best price, the fewest number of headaches, and they want things on their schedule. As a buyer in a seller’s market, here are some tips for how you can best construct an offer that gets the deal done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, sellers want their highest-priced offer to be a cash offer. However, only 25% of transactions in our MLS over the past year have been cash deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So…  If you’re a buyer that’s getting financing, how can you make your offer more attractive to a seller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could waive your appraisal contingency, or add verbiage to the agreement that shows your willingness to cover an appraisal gap. This will reassure the seller that you are doing what you can to offer as few headaches as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sellers want the best price, the fewest number of headaches, and they want things on their schedule.%20http://localhost:4000/buyer-tips-for-this-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sellers want the best price, the fewest number of headaches, and they want things on their schedule.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next.  There are a multitude of ways to reflect to a seller that you will be a stress-free buyer.  Today we’re focusing on one.  The inspection contingency.  You could shorten the timeline.  Offer to buy the home “as is.”  Or, waive the inspection contingency entirely (not that I’m suggesting that).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least.  The seller wants everything accomplished on their timeline. They likely want to close on a particular date because of the stress and hassle of moving. Sellers appreciate you giving them a few days after closing to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions at all, feel free to reach out to me and my team. We’re here to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buyer-tips-for-this-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buyer-tips-for-this-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
